Preliminary Inventory to the American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees Records, 1959-1970
Hoover Institution Archives
American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees Records,
1959-1970
70025
American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees
17 manuscript boxes (7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, and photographs, relating to relief for Tibetan refugees in Nepal and India.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Biographical/Historical Note
Private relief organization.
Access Points
International relief.; Refugees.; China.; Tibet (China)--History--1951-; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- a. AECTR combined meeting minutes - executive, financial reports, subscribers, by-laws, charter of incorporation, April 27, 1959 - December 9, 1969, (2 bound volumes). (Box 1)
- b. AECTR combined meeting minutes - executive, financial reports, subscribers, by-laws, charter of incorporation, April 27, 1959 - December 9, 1969, (11 folders).
- a. Annual reports, booklets, reprints, 1960-1969. (Box 2)
- b. Agendas, reports, April 27, 1959 - May 21, 1969.
- c. Auditors' reports, 1959-1969.
- d. Financial statements, May 31, 1959 - December 9, 1969.
- Correspondence (Box 3)
  - a. April 30 - December 31, 1959.
  - b. April 13, 1959 - December 31, 1961.
  - c. January 1 - December 31, 1960.
  - a. January 1 - June 30, 1961. (Box 4)
  - b. July 1 - December 31, 1961.
  - c. January 1 - December 31, 1962.
  - a. January 1, 1962 - December 30, 1964. (Box 5)
  - b. January 1 - December 31, 1963.
  - a. January 1 - June 30, 1964. (Box 6)
  - b. July 1 - December 31, 1964.
  - c. January 1 - June 30, 1965.
  - a. January 1, 1965 - December 31, 1966. (Box 7)
  - b. July 1 - December 31, 1965.
  - a. January 1 - December 31, 1966. (Box 8)
  - b. January 1 - December 31, 1967.
  - c. January 1, 1967 - February 28, 1968.
  - a. January 1 - May 31, 1968. (Box 9)
- General files (alphabetic)
  - b. A miscellaneous correspondence.
  - c. Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid (International Cooperation Administration).
  - d. Harry Goldberg - George Meany.
  - e. American Homes In Mussoorie, Tibet.
  - f. Art work by Tibetans.
  - g. B miscellaneous correspondence.
  - h. Brunetti, Arthur H.
  - i. C miscellaneous correspondence.
  - j. Care, Inc.
  - a. Catholic Relief Services. (Box 10)
  - b. Central Relief Committee for Tibetans.
  - c. Consent to use names, subscribers, 1959.
  - d. D miscellaneous correspondence.
  - e. Directors, Appeal to, September, 1966.
  - f. Thomas A. Dooley Foundation.
  - g. Drug lists and data.
  - h. Drug packages shipped to India, 1967.
  - a. E miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 11)
  - b. F miscellaneous correspondence.
  - c. First National City Bank, N.Y.
  - d. Fletcher, Travis L.
  - e. Foundation appeals.
  - f. Free China Relief Association, fund raising appeals.
  - g. G miscellaneous correspondence.
  - h. Geniesse, Robert J.
  - i. Gregersen, Magnus I.
  - j. H miscellaneous correspondence.
  - k. Heineman, Andrew D.
  - l. Howard, William.
  - a. I miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 12)
  - b. Indian Office receipts.
  - c. I.B.M. World Trade Corporation.
  - d. International Foundation, China.
  - e. J miscellaneous correspondence.
  - f. Judd, Walter H.
  - g. K miscellaneous correspondence.
  - h. Kripalani, Acharya - pending visit, 1960.
  - i. Honoring Dr. Kripalani, 1960.
  - a. L miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 13)
  - b. Lent, Robert F.
  - c. Liebman, Marvin.
  - d. Luce, Henry III.
  - e. Mc miscellaneous correspondence.
  - f. M miscellaneous correspondence.
  - g. Mann, Mrs. George W.
  - h. Members response to serve.
  - i. Memorandums to officers, directors and executive committee, AECTR.
  - j. Mount Hermon School receipts.
  - a. N miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 14)
  - b. New York City sales tax exemption certificate, 1965.
  - c. Newspaper clippings.
  - d. O miscellaneous correspondence.
  - e. Oram, Harold L.
  - f. P miscellaneous correspondence.
  - g. Pew Memorial Trust Fund.
  - h. Pfizer International.
  - i. Press Conferences and press releases.
  - j. Q miscellaneous correspondence.
  - k. R miscellaneous correspondence.
  - l. Readers Digest Foundation.
  - m. Reports from the field.
  - a. S miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 15)
  - b. Seattle, Washington committee of AECTR.
  - c. Shakabpa, Tsepon, family correspondence.
  - d. State Department - Refugee Migration Unit Contracts, Office of Refugee and Migration Affairs.
  - e. Stock shares - donors and acknowledgements.
  - f. T miscellaneous correspondence.
  - a. Thomas, Lowell. (Box 16)
  - b. Tibetian Boys School.
  - c. Toulouse, John (and Mrs.) D.
  - d. U miscellaneous correspondence.
  - e. U.S. Treasury Department.
  - f. Upjohn Company.
  - g. V miscellaneous correspondence.
  - h. Volunteers.
  - i. W miscellaneous correspondence.
  - j. Webb and Knapp.
  - k. Wires and cables (office copies).
  - l. X-Y-Z miscellaneous correspondence.
- AECTR photographs, (2 packages). (Box 17)